人人影视
原创翻译  双语字幕
字幕组招新中
请访问 yysub.net
翻译    better call 肉松
翻译    better call Margaery
翻译    better call 哈里不是波特
翻译    better call Eunice
翻译    better call 杏仁斯嘉丽
翻译    better call 吃冰棒
翻译    better call 子V b
翻译    better call joy_bwl
校对    better call 杏仁斯嘉丽
校对    better call Eunice
时间轴    better call 今
后期    better call 8T
总监    better call 喃喃
慢点
Slow down.
你会难受的
You're gonna make yourself sick.
要知道
You know...
我们腿下可是七百万
we're sitting on seven million bucks here.
没夸张
Literally.
怎样
And?
不如私吞了
I say we take it,
我俩五五分
split it fifty-fifty,
跑路
take off.
这不是我们的
It's not ours.
可以是
Could be.
好吧  我认识一些人
Yeah, well, I know some people
你这么做他们肯定有意见
who would have a problem with that.
他们
Them?
别担心他们
Don't worry about them.
你觉得还好吗
You feeling right?
第一件事
First thing we do,
我们要花六百万建个时光机
take six million bucks and build a time machine.
你担心的那帮人
Those people that you're worried about?
找不到我们的
They'll never find us.
你会先去哪里
Where would you go first, huh?
你看着像个历史迷  是不是
You-- You look like a history buff, right?
你会去内战时期
What, would you go to Civil War times or...
还是古罗马
Um, Ancient Rome?
天啊
Oh, Christ.
2001年12月8日
December 8, 2001.
为什么
Why?
不  不
No. No.
1984年3月17日
March 17, 1984.
那是我第一次受贿
Day I took my first bribe.
然后我会去未来
And then I'd go forward.
我想看看五年后或十年后的某些人
There's some people I'd like to check on in five or ten years,
确保他们过得不错
make sure they're doing okay.
你呢
You?
很简单
It's easy.
1965年5月10日
May 10, 1965.
那一天  沃伦·巴菲特接管了伯克希尔·哈撒韦公司
That's the day Warren Buffett took over at Berkshire Hathaway.
我觉得  造时光机还剩下了一百万
I figure, got a million left from building the time machine,
我会把我的那一半
so I'd take my half
直接投到伯克希尔
and just stick it into Berkshire.
然后回到现在
Then I'd come back here and...
就成了十亿富翁
I'm a billionaire.
有没有万亿富翁的说法
Is there such a thing as a trillionaire?
就钱吗
That's it. Money?
还有什么
What else?
你没什么想改变的吗
Nothing you'd change?
我休息好了
I'm rested.
绝命律师
第六季第十三集[全剧终]
玛丽恩  还在吗
Marion? Are you still there?
生命警报  帮助
在  是辆小轿车
Yes! It's a-- It's a little car.
米色  我不知道品牌
Beige. I-- I-- I don't know the make.
64P
Sixty-four, P...
FT6
...F, T, six.
朝南开往柯蒂斯了
He's headed south, towards Curtis.
一定要抓到他
Oh, please get him.
传往总局的消息
12-14 responding.
正在追踪嫌疑车辆
On that 10-29, V as in Victor.
是辆土星环吗
That's a Saturn Aura?
正确
That is correct.
土星环  内布拉斯加  64PFT6
Saturn Aura, Nebraska six-four-Paul-Frank-Tom-six.
白人男性  近五十岁  一米八左右  一百六十斤
White male, late 40s, about 5'11", 180 pounds.
创可贴
高档吸尘器店
"胡夫超强力吸尘器升级版  60型号"
"Hoover Max Extract Pressure-Pro, model sixty."
胡夫超强力吸尘器升级版  60型号
Hoover Pressure-Pro Max Extract, model sixty.
里面有人吗
Anybody home?
举起双手
Hands. Now.
我当时在派对上
I was at a party,
没多管闲事
just minding my own business.
你被捕了
You are under arrest.
我最好打给索尔
I better call Saul!
我是索尔·古德曼
Hi. I'm Saul Goodman.
你知道你有权利吗
Did you know that you have rights?
宪法说你有  我也说你有
The Constitution says you do, and so do I.
我相信  在被证明有罪之前
I believe that, until proven guilty,
这个国家所有的男人  女人  小孩都是无辜的
every man, woman, and child in this country is innocent.
所以我会为你而战  阿尔布开克  最好打给...
And that's why I fight for you, Albuquerque! Better Call--
喂  克丽丝塔  我是吉恩
Hello, Krista? It's Gene.
抱歉早上旷工了
Uh, uh, sorry I wasn't in this morning.
开店营业没问题吧
Did you open up okay?
我没事  能帮我个忙吗
I'm fine. C-Could you do me a favor?
这周的轮班得在三点前发出
The week's rotation needs to be posted by 3:00.
麻烦你处理下
Could you handle that?
还有就是
Uh, one more thing.
打给总部
Just call the main office.
号码在公告栏上
The-- The number is on the bulletin board.
告诉他们
And, uh, let them know, um...
你们得换个新经理了
you're gonna need a new manager.
就这样被抓了
This is how they get you?
天啊
Jesus.
你当时在想什么
What were you thinking?
你  当时  在想  什么
What... were... you... thinking?
靠
Shit!
我的律师会干死你
我得再打一个电话
I need another phone call!
再打一个电话
Another phone call!
威廉·奥克利律师事务所
William Oakley and Associates,
"相信经验  相信奥克利"
"Trust experience, trust Oakley."
我是比尔·奥克利
Bill Oakley speaking.
"相信经验  相信奥克利"
"Trust experience, trust Oakley."
我喜欢  很上口
I like that. It's catchy.
你知道我是谁吧
You know who this is, right?
索尔
Saul?
没错  老兄
You got it, buddy.
你在干什么  你在...
Wh-Wh-Wh-What are you, uh-- What-- What are y--
你...你这是干什么
Uh, wha-- Uh, what are you doing?
你明知道  你打来的话  我必须报警
Uh, you know I'm gonna have to report this call.
放松  愣头青
Calm down, Junior.
警察对这通电话再清楚不过
The cops know all about the call.
他们很可能在监听
They're probably listening in.
事实是  此时此刻我就站在
The fact is, I'm standing in the middle
警察局的中央
of a police station as we speak.
这么说他们终于抓到你了
So they finally caught you.
听好  今天你走运
Listen. This is your lucky day.
我正在跟索尔·古德曼的新咨询律师通话
I am talking to Saul Goodman's new advisory counsel.
什么
What?
跟上我的思路  比尔  你中大奖了
Keep up, Bill. You hit the jackpot.
咨询律师
"Advisory counsel?"
你就要出名了  朋友
This puts you on the map, amigo.
接下来你这么办
Here's what you're gonna do.
马上赶飞机到内布拉斯加州的奥马哈
You're gonna grab a flight to Omaha, Nebraska, ASAP.
没有直飞的航班
There's nothing direct,
你得在休斯顿转机
so you're gonna have to connect through Houston.
这钱谁付
Wh-- Who's paying for this?
-你付  听  你听到了吗  -听到什么
- You are. Listen. You hear that? - Hear what?
当  当  机会在敲门
Bang, bang! That's opportunity knocking.
赶紧起来开门
Get off your ass and answer the door.
好了  去机场的路上
Okay, on your way to the airport...
-等等  等一下  -我需要你打几个电话
- Wait. Wait. Hold on. - ...I need you to make some calls.
即便假设
Even supposing, hypothetically,
我愿意接你的案子...
I'd be willing to take this on--
还"愿意"  比尔  这是功成名就的机会
"Willing"? Bill, this is a career-maker.
现实点  你要接的
Get real. You're doing this.
地检有一仓库的证据治你的罪
The DA has a warehouse of evidence against you--
我都不敢想联调局有你多少证据
I can't even begin to imagine what the Feds are sitting on.
不管你找谁当律师  你都完蛋了
No matter who your lawyer is, you are screwed.
所以我得问一句
So I've gotta ask...
你觉得会如何收场
Where do you see this ending?
我觉得会如何收场
Where do I see it ending?
以我成功收场
With me on top.
一如往常
Like always.
道格拉斯县监狱
诈骗
Rico.
不是五项十项
Not five, not ten,
而是27项犯罪
but twenty-seven predicate violations.
在全国范围内密谋制造分销
Federal conspiracy to manufacture and distribute
管制物品
a controlled substance.
你这种规模  最高可以判终身监禁
On this scale? Life sentence, stat max.
洗钱
Money laundering.
八项  每项二十年
Eight counts, 20 years each.
最高可以判160年
One hundred sixty years, stat max.
我们会争取刑期分开连续执行
We'll argue for consecutive sentencing.
多起谋杀案的事后从犯
Accessory after the fact to multiple murders.
包括两名联邦功勋警官
Including two decorated federal officers.
每项15年
Fifteen years each.
根据我们计算  这是终身监禁外加
By our count, that's life plus...
190年有期徒刑
One hundred ninety.
终身监禁外加190年
Life plus 190 years.
好了  我愿意给你一次
All right. I'm willing to extend
爱要不要的机会
a one-time, take-it-or-leave-it offer.
听好了  30年有期徒刑
Here's the headline: 30 years.
不惹是生非  保持健康
Keep your nose clean, stay healthy,
你有可能在晚年重见天日
you have a shot at seeing daylight in your old age.
奥克利先生  你的"合伙律师"
Mr. Oakley, your "Co-counsel,"
他同意吗
is he here with us?
施罗德探员的遗孀在那边
Uh, listen, you've got Agent Schrader's widow back there.
-不如请她进来吧  -等一下...
- Why don't you invite her in? - Uh, wait a sec--
你们亏欠她的  对吧
I mean, you owe her that much, don't you?
她不能出席...
Well, no, she-- she can't be present at a--
认罪谈判  这非常不合适
a plea negotiation. It's completely inappropriate.
她人都来了
She's already here.
双方同意  没关系  真的
Both parties agree. It's fine. Really.
他们告诉我  是在垃圾箱里找到你的
They tell me they found you in a garbage dumpster.
很合理
Well, that makes sense.
我丈夫是我认识的最好的人
My husband was the best man that I have ever known.
他活着就为帮助别人
He lived to help others.
要是有人遇到困难  不管什么时间
If somebody was in trouble, no matter the time,
不管什么地点  汉克·施罗德都会帮他
no matter the place, Hank Schrader would be there.
面带微笑  不失风趣
With a smile and a joke.
他为人和善
He was kind,
体面
he was decent,
坚强
he was strong.
他的搭档
His partner...
史蒂夫·戈麦斯
Steve Gomez.
史蒂夫和布兰卡的家
Steve and Blanca
非常温馨  充满欢声笑语
made a home that was warm and full of laughter.
三个孩子
Three children.
三个失去父亲的孩子
Three fatherless children.
汉克和史蒂夫  都是好人
Hank and Steve, the good guys.
他们被枪杀
They were shot dead
扔在沙漠的坑里
and left in a hole in the desert.
而你
And you.
是你帮了
You helped
那个幕后凶手  两面派的恶毒混蛋
the two-faced poisonous bastard behind it all.
为了什么
For what?
钱
Money.
你做这些就是为了钱
You did it all for money.
不论他们现在如何处置你
No matter what they do with you now,
不论把你关在何地  关上多久
no matter where they put you or for how long,
都不够谢罪的
it will never be enough.
施罗德太太
Mrs... Mrs. Schrader.
你的丧夫之痛
The loss that you've suffered...
是无法形容的
It's unspeakable.
我见过你丈夫几次
I met your husband a few times.
他是一个一诺千金的人
He was a man who stood by his word
非常能干
and was very good at his job.
直言不讳
A straight shooter.
你和他都是
You and he are...
受害者
victims.
我也是
And so am I.
两年前一个人走进我的办公室
Two years ago a man came into my office.
他自称梅休
He said his name was Mayhew.
他想让我的一个当事人作伪证
He wanted one of my clients to lie under oath.
他承诺给我钱
He offered me money.
我拒绝了
I declined.
是律师都会拒绝的
Any lawyer would.
当天晚上我离开办公室时遭到了袭击
That night, as I was leaving my office, I was attacked.
两个人往我头上套了个袋子
Two men threw a sack over my head,
给我五花大绑
they hogtied me,
开车把我带到了沙漠里
and they drove me out into the desert.
他们把头套拿掉时
And when they pulled the hood off,
我跪在地上  面前是个挖好的坟墓
I was kneeling in front of an open grave.
头上顶着一把枪
With a gun pointed at my head.
我就是这样认识沃尔特·怀特的
That was my introduction to Walter White.
从那一刻起
From that moment on,
我没有一刻不感到害怕
there hasn't been a minute that I wasn't afraid.
没错  我是给他干活  也赚了很多钱
Yeah. I worked for him. I made a lot of money.
但我干那些并不是因为钱
But that's not why I did it.
而是因为我知道如果我拒绝  他会怎么对付我
I did it because I knew what he would do to me if I refused.
我一次又一次想过报警
Over and over, I thought about going to the police.
甚至想过找施罗德探员
I even thought about talking to Agent Schrader.
但我知道无论去了哪  沃尔特·怀特都会杀了我
But I knew that Walter White would kill me, wherever I was.
而且我是对的
And I was right.
你们去查查
You look it up.
2009年10月4日
October 4, 2009.
他们在两分钟内
They murdered ten men inside three prisons
在三个监狱里杀死了十个人
in the space of two minutes.
用刀捅死
Knifed.
割喉
Throats slashed.
一个人被活活烧死
A man was burned alive.
他们甚至杀了我的一位同行  一名律师
They even killed one of my colleagues, a lawyer.
他当时与毒品管制局合作
He was cooperating with the DEA.
丹尼尔·华兹伯格
Daniel Wachsburger.
新闻上说丹被捅了48刀
The news said Dan was stabbed 48 times.
没错  事情败露后我逃了
So, yeah, when it all blew up, I ran.
但不是躲避警方
But not from the police.
而是躲避他们
From them.
沃尔特·怀特可能是死了
Walter White might be dead,
但杰西·平克曼和其他人呢
but Jesse Pinkman and the others?
他们还在什么地方逍遥法外呢
They're still out there, somewhere.
施罗德太太...
Mrs. Schrader...
你面前是一个失去了一切的人
you are looking at a man who has lost everything.
我的职业  我的家庭  我的自由
My profession. My family. My freedom.
我...  我没有依靠
I have-- I have nobody.
我一无所有
I have nothing.
你觉得陪审团会吃你这一套吗
And you think jurors are gonna buy that?
一个
One.
只要一个人信就够了
All I need is one.
奥克利告诉我你从来没打输过官司
Oakley tells me that you've never lost a case.
是这样吗
Is that so?
了不起的记录  你应该感到自豪
That's a hell of a record. You should be proud of that.
不过...
Still...
陪审团嘛  对吧
Juries, right?
你永远也说不准
You never can tell.
就是掷骰子
It's a roll of the dice.
我只是...  我希望有点商量的余地
I'm just-- I'm hoping there's some wiggle room.
你不可以与这个人讨价还价
You are not going to negotiate with this man.
不可以
You're not.
十七
Seventeen.
被告对在此商定的罪名认罪
After sentence has been imposed on the counts
而获得相应量刑后
to which defendant pleads guilty as agreed herein,
检方将撤销
the government will move to dismiss
起诉书中第三至九项所列罪名
Counts Three through Nine of the indictment.
十八
Eighteen.
根据目前检方所掌握的事实
Based on the facts now known to the government,
预期的罪过等级是35级
the anticipated offense level is 35,
再加上
which, when combined
预期的第一类犯罪前科
with the anticipated criminal history category of 1,
综合得出的预期建议量刑区间
results in an anticipated advisory sentencing guidelines range
为入狱85到90个月
of 85 to 90 months imprisonment,
外加监外看管
in addition to any supervised release,
罚款和赔偿等法庭可能施加的处罚
fine, and restitution the Court may impose.
七年半
Seven and a half years.
我们把这玩意儿签了  赶紧结束了吧
Let's get this thing signed and get the hell out of here.
我们没意见
We're good with that.
"十九"
"Nineteen."
"将在北卡罗来纳州布特纳低戒备度监狱
"Term to be served at FCI Butner Low, North Carolina,
D区服刑"
Wing D."
布特纳低戒备度监狱
FCI Butner Low.
位置绝佳  气候宜人
It's a great location. Very nice weather.
是唯一有高尔夫活动安排的联邦监狱
It's the only federal institution with a golf program.
美国史上最大庞氏骗局制造者
伯尼·麦道夫都觉得可以接受...
It was good enough for Bernie Madoff...
你认真的吗
This is an actual request?
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
我稍微一不留神
I give you guys half a chance,
你们就会把我扔进关普通囚犯的鬼地方去
you're gonna throw me into gen pop in some hellhole.
我曾经去过蒙特罗斯超级监狱看望某个委托人
I visited a client once at ADX Montrose.
"洛基山脉的恶魔岛"
"The Alcatraz of the Rockies."
不行不行  这条绝对不能让步  朋友
No. No, that's a dealbreaker, my friend.
布特纳低戒备度监狱...
FCI Butner Low. Wing...
D  是D区
D. Wing D.
"D区"
"Wing D."
就这样了
And now we are done.
就像史蒂夫·乔布斯经常说的  还有一项
Ah, as Steve Jobs used to say, one more thing.
"二十"
"Twenty."
"监禁期间  被告古德曼
"During incarceration, Defendant Goodman to receive
每周五将得到600毫升蓝铃牌薄荷口味
one pint Blue Bell mint chocolate chip ice cream
带巧克力碎的冰激凌"
every Friday for the duration."
你开玩笑呢吧
Are you kidding?
他开玩笑呢
He's kidding.
"蓝铃牌薄荷口味带巧克力碎"
"Blue Bell Mint Chocolate Chip."
不得替换
No substitutions.
好  就这样吧
Okay. That's it.
等等  我可以让大家都更满意
Hold on. I can oil everybody's locks.
-别玩把戏了  -不是  我还有个甜头呢
- No more games. - No. I got a sweetener.
是我之前没讲过的
It's nothing I've talked about.
新的领域  重大爆料
New arena. Primo stuff.
说吧
Go.
内幕信息
Inside story,
之前没被发现的重大杀人案
previously unknown felony homicide.
事关阿尔布开克一位著名的律师
It concerns a prominent Albuquerque attorney
他失踪了
who, uh, disappeared,
据信是自杀了
believed to have killed himself.
霍华德·哈姆林
Howard Hamlin?
你说的是霍华德·哈姆林
You're talking about Howard Hamlin.
这就是你的"甜头"
That's your "Sweetener"?
他想用哈姆林的事说服我们
He's trying to sell us the Hamlin thing.
他还以为自己真有筹码
He thought he really had something.
听起来你和你前妻不常聊天啊
Sounds like you and your ex aren't talking on a regular basis.
金·韦克斯勒上个月走进阿尔布开克地检办公室
Kim Wexler walked into the Albuquerque DA's office last month.
她把霍华德·哈姆林的事全公开交代出来了
She spilled her guts about Howard Hamlin, on the record.
你没有筹码了
You got nothing left to sell.
最后一次机会
Last chance.
上庭受审还是接受认罪协议
Do we go to trial, or do we have a deal?
好
Yes!
我们接受
Yes, we have a deal.
把协议写下来
Let's get this in writing.
一个字也不能改
Not a word changes.
当然了
Of course.
我要是问你在干嘛  我会不会后悔
Am I gonna be sorry if I ask what's going on?
我要让这个停下来
I'm putting a stop to it.
让什么停下来
A stop to what?
你还问
To what?
你听  别说话  仔细听
Listen. Just-- No. Just listen.
这咔哒声
That click?
就是这咔哒声
The click.
火能打着
The flame is lighting
但是不断熄灭
and then it keeps going out.
所以要么是热电偶腐蚀了
So it's either a thermocouple that's corroded
要么是短路了
or we have a short.
热电偶腐蚀  好  我知道了
A thermocouple is corroded. Okay. I got it.
也许我们可以拔掉电源插头
Hey, uh, maybe we could just unplug it?
-或是剪断电线  -不  听好了
- Or cut a wire or something? - No. Listen.
我没理由待在地底下  没有热水用
I see no reason to stay down here without hot water
明明我轻易就能修好它
when it's something that I can easily fix.
这个应该能行
I think this will do the trick.
你那些行李袋里有没有小折刀
You wouldn't happen to have a pocket knife or a screwdriver
或螺丝刀
in one of those bags, would you?
没有
No.
什么  大声点
What? Speak up!
没有
No.
加把劲啊
Come on!
好了
There we go.
这个应该管用
Yeah. This should work.
你是科学家  对吧
Hey, you're a scientist, right?
我想问个问题
So, uh, I have a question.
如果你有时光机  你会怎么做
What would you do if you had a time machine?
时光机
A time machine?
是的
Yeah, um...
从科学家的角度来看
From a scientist's point of view.
你可以回到过去  或是前往未来
You can go backwards, forwards.
你会去哪里
Uh, where would you go?
这问题毫无意义
A meaningless question.
还时...
Time--
时光机呢
A time machine.
听着  时间旅行
Look, time travel,
你在想的这种时间旅行
the kind of time travel that you're thinking of,
从科学上来讲是不可能的
is a scientific impossibility.
那会违反热力学第二定律
It would violate the Second Law of Thermodynamics.
那虫洞呢
Uh, but what about a wormhole?
我之前看科学节目时  男星艾伦·阿尔达认为...
Well, I was watching NOVA, and Alan Alda seemed to think--
那艾伦·阿尔达就是专家咯
Oh, well, then Alan Alda, he's the expert.
老天  开什么玩笑
Oh, Christ. Are you kidding me?
量子力学  我们现在讨论起这个吗
Quantum mechanics? We're discussing that now?
少管闲事
Stay in your lane.
就是个思想实验
It's just a thought experiment.
如果可以做到  你一定有什么事
There's gotta be something you'd go back and change
是想回去改变的吧
if you could.
你不是在说时光机
Oh, you are not talking about a time machine,
那在现实中和理论上都是不可能的
which is both a real and theoretical impossibility.
你是在谈论后悔
You are talking about regrets.
如果你想问我有没有后悔的事
So if you want to ask about regrets,
那就直接问
just ask about regrets
不要扯时间旅行那些鬼话
and leave all this time-traveling nonsense out of it.
好  那就说后悔事
Okay. Regrets, then.
后悔事
Regrets.
对
Yeah.
让我后悔的事
My regrets. All right, well...
My regrets...
那个
Well...
我读研究生的时候
When I was a graduate student,
我创立了一家公司  和几个...
I started a company with some...
我当时视为朋友的人
At the time, I thought they were my friends.
我们的目标是将我的研究成果商业化
Our goal was to commercialize discoveries that I had made.
到了某个阶段
And at a certain point...
我退出了
I stepped away.
我以为这是绅士之举
I thought I was doing the gentlemanly thing.
但我没想到
But little did I understand
是他们精心操纵我
that they were artfully maneuvering me
让我抛下了我的创作
into leaving my own creation.
要是我当初留下来了
And had I stayed, oh...
那么
Well...
我现在就不会和你一起被困在地下
I wouldn't be down here with you.
你创立了一家公司  它还在吗
So you started a company. Is it still around?
在
Oh, yes.
成功吗
Is it successful?
非常成功
Very.
你怎么从来没跟我说过
How could you never tell me about this?
我们本可以采取些行动的
We could have done something with this.
告他们不当解雇  盗窃知识产权
Wrongful termination, intellectual property theft,
专利诈骗
uh, patent fraud.
我可以拿这个案子大做文章的
I mean, I coulda sunk my teeth into this!
我要找律师也绝对不会找你
You'd have been the last lawyer I'd have gone to.
那倒是
Yeah. Sure.
你呢
So, what about you?
-什么  -后悔事
- What? - Regrets?
等等  我想到一件
Y-- Wait. I got one.
算了  当我没问
You know what? Never mind.
我20岁那年
When I was 20--
是22岁
um, 22,
我在百货商店门外想假摔碰瓷
I pulled a slip and fall outside Marshall Field's.
真的
I did.
我那时年少无脑  就想卖弄
And I was stupid and young and I was trying to show off.
所以我以最快速度砸向冰面
So I hit the ice as fast as I could.
我摔得那么狠  听见一声脆响
I biffed it so hard, I heard a crack!
不是冰碎了  而是我
Wasn't the ice, it was me.
我伤到了自己
I actually hurt myself.
从那以后我的膝盖就落下毛病了
I mean, I-- My knee has never been the same.
"碰瓷"
"A slip and fall"?
对  我上调酒学校的学费就是这样挣出来的
Yeah. That's how I put myself through bartending school.
嗯
Right.
这么说...
So...
你一直爱搞歪门邪道
So you were always like this.
不好意思
Sorry.
比尔
Bill! Hey.
-我正要...  -先生  这个人是联邦囚犯
- I'm just going to-- - Sir, this man is a federal prisoner.
我是法警
I'm a US Marshal.
请你不要跟他说话
I ask you not to speak to him.
他是我的律师
That's my lawyer.
是吗  你是他的律师
Is that true? You're his lawyer?
是的
Yes.
以后你会有机会跟你委托人说话的
You'll have other opportunities to talk to your client.
请你不要挡着过道
Please move out of the aisle.
不  等等
No, hold on.
我当着你面说的话都不是保密的  对吧
N-Nothing I say in front of you is privileged, right?
是的
That's right.
所以如果我跟我律师说话的时候
So if I talk to my attorney and we let something slip
无意中泄露了对检方有利的信息
that could help the government's case,
你可以给公诉人传话
you could pass it along to the prosecution.
完全没问题
Totally clean.
没错
Correct.
这样的话  我们真的不能说两句吗
With that in mind, you're sure we can't have a few words?
长话短说
Make it fast.
她认罪了  地检打算怎么做
She confessed. What's the DA gonna do with it?
没有证人  没有确凿证据
No witnesses, no physical evidence.
要我猜的话  他们很可能就把这案子晾在一旁
If I had to guess, most likely they sit on it.
永久地晾在一旁
Permanently.
好
Okay.
不  不"好"
No, not "Okay."
对她来说不好  她的问题不在于地检
Not for her. Her problem's not the DA.
那是什么
What then?
金把她的宣誓公证证词
Well, apparently, Kim took her sworn and notarized statement
亲手交给了哈姆林的遗孀
and hand delivered it to Hamlin's widow.
-不是吧  -就是
- No. - Yes.
她自愿接受民事诉讼
She opened herself up to a civil suit.
哈姆林的遗孀可以拿走她现在和以后
The widow can take her for everything she has
所拥有的一切  永远如此
and everything she's gonna have, in perpetuity.
那她会起诉吗
So, is she? Suing?
有一件事我可以肯定地告诉你
Look, all I can tell you for sure
我们说话这会儿  哈姆林太太正在四处召集律师
is that Mrs. Hamlin's out lawyer shopping as we speak.
虽然她是没找我啦
Not that she bothered to call me.
我现在可以去厕所了吗
Hey, can I, uh, go to the john now?
我去了
I'm going.
等一下  比尔
Hold up, Bill.
等等  你肯定想听这个
No, wait. You're gonna love this.
哈姆林的事  检方只是一知半解
The Hamlin thing? The government doesn't know the half of it.
我们一落地
As soon as we land,
你就告诉他们
I want you to tell the other side
我还有谈判筹码  明白吗
that I've got more to trade, okay?
我刚想起来一些能让他们兴奋的事
I j-just remembered something that'll make their toes curl.
好
Okay.
能让他们兴奋的事肯定对金不利
Anything that makes their "Toes curl" is bound to jam Kim up.
如果与她有关的话
If it involves her.
与她有关
Oh, it involves her.
金已经面临民事诉讼了
Kim's already got a civil suit hanging over her head.
你再向检方透露猛料
You give the government more,
她可能会受到重罚
maybe they bring the hammer down.
你还能得到什么好处
What more are you gonna get?
还剩下什么
What's left?
你不明白
You don't understand.
那冰激凌真的很好吃
It's really good ice cream.
-又是男孩吗  -这次是女孩
- Boys again? - Girls this time.
她接下来一两年别想睡觉了
Well, she's not sleeping for a year or two.
-一两年都算少说  -她还回来吗
- At least. - Is she coming back?
她不得不回来
She'll have to.
乔什是双胞胎  对吧
Josh is a twin, isn't he?
对  他下周过生日
Oh, yeah. And it's his birthday next week.
我总是带他出门庆祝  就我俩
I always take him out, just the two of us,
因为他小时候什么都得和他的双胞胎兄弟分享
because, you know, he had to share everything.
那真好
Well, that's nice.
要么去红龙虾餐厅
It's either Red Lobster
要么就去威克姆那边新开的中东菜餐厅
or that new Middle Eastern place, the one over on Wickham.
-叫托普什么什么  -托普卡皮
- Top something? - Topkapi.
没错  托普卡皮
That's it. Topkapi.
格伦带你去过  对吧  那家怎么样
Glen took you there, didn't he? What'd you guys think?
那里不...
Uh, it wasn't...
不太好  是吗
Not good, huh?
不  挺好的
No, uh... No. It was fine.
乔什会喜欢吗
Would Josh like it?
可能吧
He-- He might.
好  那就再在红龙虾过生日
Okay. Another birthday at Red Lobster.
他不会有意见
He can live with that.
送礼聚会的时候我们送他们什么来着  婴儿车吧
What did we get them for the shower? A stroller, right?
是的  带减震器的高级货
Yeah, one of the nice ones with the shock absorbers.
双胞胎的话他们可能需要双人婴儿车
With twins? They might need a double stroller...
你也是  多尼
You, too, Donny.
席安娜  锯齿草球场的多尼找你  四号线
Seana, Donny from TPC Sawgrass, line four.
从1978年开始浇灌你的世界
谭美  我早走一会儿  你帮我告诉里卡多好吗
Hey, Tammy. I'm leaving early. Can you let Ricardo know?
-好  没问题  -谢谢
- Sure. No prob. - Thanks.
棕榈海岸洒水器
Palm Coast Sprinkler.
从1978年开始浇灌你的世界
Watering your world since 1978.
如果他出现  你千万别开门
If he shows up, you keep that door locked.
报警  然后给我打电话
You call the police, and then you call me.
任何时候都行  不管白天晚上
Any time, day or night.
明白吗
Okay?
-明白  -周四见
- Okay. - I'll see you Thursday.
需要我开车接你的话就告诉我
Let me know if you need me to pick you up.
-好  谢谢  -好的
- All right. Thank you. - Okay.
女士们  这边请
Ladies, it's right this way.
抱歉这里很热  空调坏了
Sorry about the heat. AC's on the fritz.
把这个填了  还有  省得你问  不收费
Fill this out. And, before you ask, there's no charge.
我们所有服务都是免费的
All our services are free.
其实  我是来问我能不能在这做志愿者
Oh, a-actually, I'm here to see if I can volunteer.
你想做志愿者
You want to volunteer?
是的
Yes.
你会接电话吗
Can you answer a phone?
当然
Sure.
那这通电话你接
Then there you go.
中佛罗里达法律援助  有什么可以帮助你
Central Florida Legal Aid. How can I help you?
委托人档案
-喂  -金吗
- Hello? - Kim?
-我是  -我是苏姗娜·埃里克森
- Yes. - This is Suzanne Ericsen.
你好  苏珊娜
Hi, Suzanne.
先说清楚
I want to make it clear
我这是私下联系你
this call is completely unofficial.
好
All right.
我压根就不应该跟你说话
I shouldn't even be talking to you.
不过综合考虑
But considering everything,
我觉得还是应该把事情告诉你
I think it's only right you know what's going on.
你看到新闻没
You've seen the news?
应该没有
I don't think so.
你的前夫  那个"索尔·古德曼"
Your ex, "Saul Goodman"?
他在内布拉斯加州被捕了
He was arrested in Nebraska.
现在已经被引渡到新墨西哥州
He's been extradited to New Mexico.
什么时候的事
When was this?
两天前
Two days ago.
不过我打电话来不是要说这个
But that's not why I'm calling.
他会给出一些对你个人有影响的证词
He's giving testimony that affects you, personally.
什么样的证词
What kind of testimony?
表演时间到
It's showtime.
全体起立  有请尊敬的萨曼莎·斯默法官
All rise for the right honorable Judge Samantha Small.
现在开庭  请坐
Court's now in session. Please take a seat.
今天第一件事
Okay, item one on the calendar,
案件CR10-7253美利坚合众国诉...
CR 10-7253 United States of America versus...
被告要求使用索尔·古德曼这个姓名
Defendant has requested to use the name Saul Goodman.
所以是"美国诉索尔·古德曼"
So it's "United States versus Saul Goodman."
律师  请说明你方出庭人员
Counsel, please state your appearances.
乔治·卡斯特拉诺联邦检察官
AUSA George Castellano.
我身旁的是伊丽莎白·诺亚迪
With me is Elizabeth Nooryani,
司法部缉毒科的
Trial Attorney from
诉讼律师
the Drug Enforcement Section of the Department of Justice,
三位联邦检察官莎拉·布拉多克
AUSAs Sarah Braddock,
尼尔·帕特尔和希拉里·帕克
Neel Patel, and Hillary Park
缉毒局特别行动组的奥斯丁·雷米组长
and Special Agent in Charge Austin Ramey from the DEA.
出席的还有
Also present in the courtroom,
新墨西哥州联调局特别行动组组长
Zachary Hernandez, Special Agent in Charge
扎克里·赫尔南德斯
of the FBI in New Mexico.
另外  法官大人  受害者
Your Honor, I'd also like to note the presence of the victims
也出席了本庭
who are here this morning,
玛丽·施罗德和布兰卡·戈麦斯
Marie Schrader and Blanca Gomez.
威廉·奥克利以顾问律师身份出席
William Oakley appearing as advisory counsel.
索尔·古德曼为自己辩护
Saul Goodman appearing on his own behalf.
早上好
Good morning.
被告仍希望为自己辩护吗
The defendant still wants to represent himself?
是的  法官大人
Uh... That's right, your Honor.
好的
Okay.
双方已充分协商
The parties have reached a plea agreement
达成了认罪协议
satisfactory to both sides.
不过  看完
However, I have reviewed
检方给出的量刑建议后
the government's sentencing recommendations and...
我有疑问
well, I have questions.
卡斯特拉诺先生  烦请移步至话筒前
Mr. Castellano, will you please come up to the microphone?
卡斯特拉诺先生  我们今天判决的这位被告
Mr. Castellano, today we consider the sentence
将要承认的罪行包括
for a defendant who will be pleading guilty
多项重罪  诈骗
to multiple felonies, RICO offenses,
洗钱  同谋及事后协助
money laundering, conspiracy, accessory after the fact
谋杀数名联邦警官
to the murder of federal officers.
这些罪名
And for these offenses,
检方给出的量刑建议却只有七年
the government's sentencing recommendation is seven years.
法官大人
Your Honor,
我可以保证  我和同事们
I can assure you my colleagues and I
已经对各方面进行了详尽的综合考虑
gave every aspect of this recommendation careful consideration.
别担心  斯默法官一向遵循检方的量刑建议
请详细说明一下
Help me understand.
被告是否为检方
Has the defendant provided
提供了实质性的帮助
substantial assistance to the government?
法官大人
Your Honor?
奥克利先生  请建议你的委托人
Mr. Oakley, please advise your client
此时保持沉默
to stay silent at this time.
尊敬的法官大人  奥克利先生是顾问律师
Your Honor, with respect, Mr. Oakley is advisory counsel.
今天我为自己辩护
I'm representing myself here today.
我认为能帮助法庭充分了解情况
If I may say something that I think will help the court
请允许我发言
fully understand the situation?
古德曼先生  你是受惠者
Mr. Goodman, you are the beneficiary
我担任法官22年来
of the most generous sentencing recommendation
都没见过如此慷慨的量刑建议
I've seen in 22 years on the bench.
你所做的任何陈述只会危及该建议
Any statement you make imperils that recommendation.
我非常清楚  法官大人
I'm very aware of that, Your Honor.
如果您允许我发言
Uh, if you'll allow me to speak,
我觉得可以为本法庭节省宝贵的时间
I-- I think I can save the court's valuable time.
请讲
Go ahead.
长话短说
Briefly.
两年前  一个男人走进我的办公室
Two years ago a man came into my office.
他说他叫梅修
He said his name was Mayhew.
他要我的一位委托人替他做伪证
He wanted one of my clients to lie for him under oath.
他给我钱  我拒绝了
He offered me money. I refused.
那一晚  我离开办公室时  遭到了袭击
That night, as I was leaving my office, I was attacked.
我的头被套上了一个麻袋
A bag was shoved over my head,
我被五花大绑
I was hogtied,
载到了沙漠里
I was driven out into the desert.
他们摘下麻袋后
And when they pulled the hood off,
我发现自己跪在一座挖好的坟墓前
I was kneeling in front of an open grave
被抢指着头
with a gun pointed at my head.
那就是我对沃尔特·怀特的最初印象
That was my introduction to Walter White!
我当时害怕极了
I was terrified.
但是很快就不怕了
But not for long.
那一晚  我看见了机遇
That night, I saw opportunity.
一个赚大钱的机遇
A shot at big money.
我就紧紧地抓住了它
And I grabbed it and I held it tight.
在后来的十六个月里
And for the next 16 months,
我的每个清醒时刻
my every waking moment was
都用来打造沃尔特·怀特的毒品帝国
spent building Walter White's drug empire.
等等  古德曼先生  打住
Hold on, Mr. Goodman. Stop right there.
你先咨询完奥克利先生再说话
Consult Mr. Oakley before you say another word.
法官大人  我认为应当在法庭说出真相
Your Honor, I believe the court deserves the whole truth.
你这番话  跟你在认罪协议里
You are contradicting your plea agreement's
宣誓证明过的事实依据自相矛盾
sworn factual basis.
恕我直言  法官大人
No offense, Your Honor, but I--
这方面的法律我比您更清楚
I think I know the law here better than you do.
法官大人  我们申请休庭
Your Honor, we'd like to request a recess.
不  我们不需要休庭
No, we do not need a recess.
法官大人  我们对古德曼先生继续发言没意见
Your Honor, we are satisfied for Mr. Goodman to continue.
法官大人
Your Honor,
我请求退出此案
I'd like to petition to withdraw from this case.
-驳回  -我很恳切...
- Denied. - Respectfully--
不可能
Not a chance.
鲍比  给古德曼先生宣誓
Bobbi, swear Mr. Goodman in.
你愿发誓在法庭上
Do you swear that the evidence
就此事给出的证据
you shall give to the court in this matter
字字属实
shall be the truth, the whole truth,
绝无虚言  愿主佑你吗
and nothing but the truth so help you God?
我发誓
I do.
古德曼先生  你现在发过誓了
Mr. Goodman, you are now under oath.
你的任何虚假证词
Any false statement you make
都可能用于起诉你
can be used in prosecution
作伪证和妨碍司法
for perjury or obstruction of justice.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
-明白  -好的
- Yes. - All right.
在过去的二十四小时内
In the last 24 hours,
你有摄入任何酒精或是毒品吗
have you used any alcohol or other drugs?
没有  法官大人
No, Your Honor.
你有服用任何处方药物吗
Are you taking any prescription medications?
没有
No.
好
All right.
请继续
Continue.
关于金·韦克斯勒  我向检方撒了谎
Oh, um, I lied to the government about, uh, Kim Wexler.
我跟他们说了一堆
Uh, I fed them a load of BS
她卷入了霍华德·哈姆林谋杀案的胡话
about her involvement in Howard Hamlin's murder.
我这么做是想让她今天能来
I just-- I just wanted her to come here today.
我想让她听我说
I wanted her to hear this.
没错  制冰毒的时候我不在场
So, yeah, I wasn't there when the meth was cooked.
销售的时候我不在场
I wasn't there when it was sold.
任何一起谋杀发生时我都不在场
I didn't witness any of the murders,
但我很清楚地知道发生了这些事
but I damn well knew it was happening.
我不仅仅自愿参与其中
I was more than a willing participant.
我更是不可或缺的一分子
I was indispensable.
我保沃尔特·怀特不进监狱
I kept Walter White out of jail,
我帮他洗钱
I laundered his money,
我替他撒谎  给他出谋划策
I lied for him, I conspired with him,
我赚得盆满钵满
and I made millions.
如果他那天没有走进我的办公室
If he hadn't walked into my office that day,
沃尔特·怀特不出一个月就会
Walter White would have been dead
要么死翘翘  要么蹲大牢
or behind bars within a month.
而施罗德探员和戈麦斯探员
And Agent Schrader and Agent Gomez
以及其他许多人也不会死去
and a whole lot of other people would still be alive.
事实就是  沃尔特·怀特没了我就不可能成功
Fact is, Walter White couldn't have done it without me.
记好了吗
You got that?
法官大人  我们请求删去古德曼先生的发言
Your Honor, we move to strike Mr. Goodman's comments.
基于何种理由
On what grounds?
-这是推测  -推测
- Um, speculation. - Speculation?
他在为自己的行为作证
He's testifying to his own actions.
法官大人  他描述的都是
Your Honor, uh, he's describing events
在假设他做法不同的前提下才会发生的事
that would have transpired had he acted differently.
我还有一件事要说
I have one more thing to say.
-坐下  古德曼先生  马上  -拜托了  法官大人
- Sit down, Mr. Goodman. Now. - Please, your Honor. Please.
请法警带古德曼先生回原位
Will Marshal please remove Mr. Goodman from the podium.
检方敦促本庭允许古德曼先生继续发言
The government urges the court to allow Mr. Goodman to continue.
这怎么不是推测呢
How is that not speculation?
那好吧  古德曼先生
All right, Mr. Goodman.
你继续
Go ahead.
霍华德·哈姆林的遭遇...
What happened to Howard Hamlin was...
实在是...
it was...
我没办法说出口...
I can't even...
在那之后
After that,
金有勇气重新来过
Kim had the guts to start over.
她远走高飞了  但其实...
She left town, but...
我才是真正逃避的那个人
I'm the one who ran away.
至于我的哥哥查克
And my brother Chuck--
查尔斯·麦吉尔
Uh, Charles McGill.
您可能知道他
Y-You may have known him.
他是位了不起的律师
He was an incredible lawyer, as--
我见过的最厉害的人
The most brilliant guy I ever met.
但他也有局限
But he was limited.
我尽力了
I tried.
我本可以更努力的
I could have tried harder.
我应该更努力一点的
I should have.
-然而...  -法官大人
- Instead, when-- - Your Honor.
比尔  拜托  让我说完吧
Bill, please. Just let me get through this.
然而  我发现有机会伤害他时  我行动了
Instead, when I saw a chance to hurt him, I took it.
我害他丢了职业过失保险
I got his malpractice insurance canceled.
我夺走了他活下去的唯一指望
I took away the one thing he lived for,
法律
the law.
之后他自杀了
After that, he killed himself.
而我得背负着歉疚苟活
And I'll live with that.
你这是干什么
What was all that?
你哥哥的事  根本就不是犯罪啊
That thing with your brother, that wasn't even a crime.
是犯罪
Yeah, it was.
古德曼先生  坐好了别动
Mr. Goodman, sit down and stay seated.
是麦吉尔
The name's McGill.
我叫詹姆斯·麦吉尔
I'm James McGill.
法官大人  鉴于被告的供词
Your Honor, in view of the defendant's confession,
法官大人  我们想申请休庭
Your Honor, we'd like to request a recess--
检方在此撤回量刑建议
the Government withdraws its sentencing recommendation.
不  等一下
No. No, hold on.
那不是供词
That was not a confession.
并敦促本庭对每项罪名
And urges this court to impose the statutory maximum
他说的...他说的不是供词
That was... That was not a confession.
判处法定最高年限的监禁期
for each of these offenses.
那只不过是以复杂的叙述方式...
It was merely, uh, a single point of view...
此外  法官大人
Furthermore, your Honor,
需要举行第二次额外听证会
a second additional hearing is required...
所表达的一种观点
in a very complex, uh, narrative.
请容我补充  该观点
A point of view, I might add, that is presented without
没有任何证据支持
a single shred of evidence.
以评估古德曼先生...
to assess the additional claims Mr. Goodman--
抱歉  是麦吉尔先生现在承认的额外罪名
I'm sorry-- Mr. McGill has now admitted to,
包括在本庭作伪证  法官大人
including perjury on this court, your Honor.
你放电了吗
Did you ground yourself?
放了
Yes, I did!
该死
Oh, crap!
我都开始担心了
I was starting to worry.
我的车在四十号公路上抛锚了
My car conked out on the 40.
我差点被一辆水泥车压扁
I almost got creamed by a cement truck.
他们有卖你喜欢的那种苹果
They had those apples that you like.
我帮你买了半打富士
I got you half a dozen Fuji.
中央大街的报摊小贩说
Um, and the newsstand on Central
他们可能要卖《金融时报》了
said they might start carrying the Financial Times.
好消息  是不是
So that's good, right?
怎么了
What?
你知道我可以雇人来做这些事的
You know I could hire someone to do this.
我可以从办公室里找个人
I could get someone from the office.
我来做就行
I'm doing it.
每天吗
Yeah, every day?
你不是打算开一间律师事务所
While you're trying to start a...practice?
为什么
Why?
还用问吗
因为你是我哥哥
'Cause you're my brother.
你也会为我这么做的
You'd do the same for me.
好吧  你可以在这待一会
Mm. Well, you could stay for a while.
我们可以聊聊
We could talk.
聊聊  聊什么
Talk? What about?
你的案子  你的委托人
Well, your cases. Your clients.
你想聊我的委托人
You want to talk about my clients?
真的吗  你想聊
Seriously? You want to talk about, uh,
在基督教科学阅览室里拉客
the granny who got picked up for soliciting
而被抓的老太太
inside a Christian Science Reading Room?
还是闯进酒铺
Wh-- What about the kid who broke into a liquor store
喝了五瓶薄荷甜酒
and drank five bottles of creme de menthe
然后昏倒在柜台后面的小子
and then passed out behind the counter?
他们理应得到有力的辩护
They deserve a vigorous defense.
跟其他委托人一样
Like any other client.
或者你只是想告诉我我哪里做错了
Or maybe you just wanna tell me what I'm doing wrong.
我没有这么想
That's not what I had in mind.
我希望这冰不是你从汽车旅馆的制冰机偷来的
I'm hoping you didn't steal that from a motel ice machine.
没准真不是呢
You can hope.
促膝谈心什么的还是算了吧  查克
I'm gonna take a pass on the heart-to-heart, Chuck.
我其中一个"理应得到我帮助"的委托人
One of my "deserving" clients,
被抓到在工艺品店外面挥舞他的小腊肠
he got caught waving the weenie outside a Hobby Lobby.
等一下  我得把费用给你报销了
Hold on. You got to reimburse yourself.
这次算我的
Mm. This one's on me.
吉米
Jimmy...
如果你不喜欢现在这条路
If you don't like where you're heading,
那回过头去换一条路也并不可耻
there's no shame in going back and changing your path.
你什么时候改变过你的道路
Uh, when have you ever "changed your path"?
你慢慢想
Hey. Think on it.
我们最后都在聊一样的话  对吗
We always end up having the same conversation, don't we?
明天见  查克
I'll see ya tomorrow, Chuck.
我可能会带《金融时报》来
And I might have the Financial Times.
《时间机器》
赫伯特·乔治·威尔斯著
囚犯
玫瑰山超级戒备联邦监狱
下一出口
不要让人搭便车
我认识你吗
I know you?
"最好打给索尔"
"Better Call Saul."
是你吧
Right?
麦吉尔
McGill.
什么
What?
我叫麦吉尔
I'm McGill.
别跟我来这套
Don't give me that.
你就是索尔
You're Saul!
是"最好打给索尔"
It's Better Call Saul.
真的假的
No shit.
你  回头
Back here, yo.
转过来
Back here.
看到没  就跟你说
See? Toldja!
是最好打给索尔
It's Better Call Saul!
你说得对  最好打给索尔
You're right. Better Call Saul.
没错  最好打给索尔
Yeah. Better Call Saul.
最好
Better...
打给
Call...
索尔
Saul.
最好
Better...
打给
Call...
索尔
Saul.
最好打给索尔
Better Call Saul!
-都闭嘴  -最好打给索尔
- All of you, shut up! - Better Call Saul!
-最好打给索尔  -闭嘴
- Better Call Saul! - I said shut up!
-最好打给索尔  -都他妈闭嘴
- Better Call Saul! - Shut the hell up!
-最好打给索尔  -闭嘴
最好打给索尔
Better Call Saul!
最好打给...
Better Call...
索尔  律师来了
Saul! Lawyer's here!
交给我吧  索尔
I got ya, Saul.
-女士  -麻烦解开手铐
- Ma'am? - No cuffs, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
吉米
Hi, Jimmy.
你是怎么...
How did you...
原来我的新墨西哥州律师证
Uh, turns out my New Mexico bar card
没写有效期限
doesn't have an expiration date.
你本来已经把刑期减到七年了
You had them down to seven years.
是啊
Yeah, I did.
八十六年
Eighty-six years.
但如果表现好的话...
But with good behavior...
谁知道呢
who knows?